Gianluca Castignani - Curriculum Vitae

Contact Information Observatoire de Paris

LERMA

61 avenue de l'Observatoire

E-mail: gianluca.castignani at obspm.fr

75014 Paris, France webpage: https://sites.google.com/site/gianlucacastignani/home

Role in the PROJECT

I will investigate the role of the environment on processing gas in Virgo filament galaxies by means of both interferometric high-spatial resolution observations in mm (I am the PI of a NOEMA proposal) and clustering analyses. I will also contribute to the project on high-z galaxy clusters. The proposed contribution will benefit mainly from my experience on radio-loud AGNs and distant clusters.

Current position Postdoc

Observatoire de Paris, LERMA

12/2016 - present

Laboratoire d'Etudes du Rayonnement et de la Matiére en Astrophysique et Atmosphéres

Collège de France 12/2016 - present

• Advisor: Françoise Combes

FORMER POSITION

Centre National d'Études Spatiales (CNES) postdoctoral fellow

Laboratorie Lagrange, Observatoire de la Côte d'Azur, Nice, France 12/2014 - 11/2016

EDUCATION

PhD in Astrophysics, SISSA, Trieste, Italy	11/2010 - 10/2014
MSc in Physics, University of Pisa, Italy	07/2008 - 10/2010
BSc in Physics, University of Pisa, Italy	09/2005 - 07/2008
Student in Physics, Scuola Normale Superiore, Pisa, Italy	10/2005 - 09/2010

WORK EXPERIENCE

12/2014 - 11/2016 Laboratorie Lagrange, Observatoire de la Côte d'Azur, Nice, France Euclid consortium, Ground Segment Workpackage Clusters of Galaxies 06/2015 - present Dark Energy Survey (DES), DES-Brasil consortium, LIneA node 10/2016 - present 2010 - 2014 Altogether 1 year research period at the *STScI* (Baltimore, USA)

Fellowships, HONORS, AND AWARDS

Marie Sklodowska-Curie Actions (MSCA) 2017. Seal of Excellence. Score = 87.20%. 03/201811/2014 - 11/2016 CNES postdoctoral fellowship Ph.D. fellowship at SISSA 11/2010 - 10/2014 04/2014 - 06/2014 Fondazione Angelo Della Riccia Fellowship (3,500 euro) to work at the STScI Fondazione Angelo Della Riccia Fellowship (1,800 euro) to work at the STScI 03/2013 - 10/2013 ISSNAF/INAF internship to work at the STScI 07/2010 - 09/2010 10/2005 - 09/2010 Scholarship at the Scuola Normale Superiore, Pisa, Italy Competitor at the Italian Olympiads of Physics for high school students, after qualification 2005 Competitor at the Italian Olympiads of Mathematics for high school students, after qualification 2005

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS IN REFEREED JOURNALS

G. Castignani, E. Pian, et al. Multifrequency variability study of the gamma-ray emitting blazar PKS 1510-089, 2017, arXiv:1612.05281, A&A in press • G. Castignani & C. Benoist, A new method to assign galaxy cluster membership using photometric redshifts, 2016, A&A, 595, 111 • G. Castignani & G. De Zotti, AGN torus emission for a homogeneous sample of bright flat spectrum radio quasars, 2015, A&A, 573, 125 • G. Castignani, M. Chiaberge, A. Celotti, & C. Norman, A new method to search for high redshift clusters using photometric redshifts, 2014, ApJ, 792, 113 • G. Castignani, M. Chiaberge, A. Celotti, C. Norman, & G. De Zotti, Cluster candidates around low power radio-galaxies at $z \sim 1-2$ in COSMOS, 2014, ApJ, 792, 114 • G. Castignani, D. Guetta, E. Pian, L. Amati, S. Puccetti, and S. Dichiara, Time delays between Fermi-LAT and GBM light curves of gamma-ray bursts, 2014, A&A, 56, 60 • G. Castignani, F. Haardt, A. Lapi, G. De Zotti, A. Celotti, and L. Danese, Black hole mass estimates for a homogeneous sample of bright flat-spectrum radio quasars, 2013, A&A, 560, 28